Mikhail Tsoy

+381631256794 | mikhail.tsoy123@gmail.com | Belgrade, Serbia

Summary

Frontend developer with over 1 year of experience.

As a versatile frontend developer and ex-UX/UI designer, I have a strong foundation in HTML, CSS, JS, and React.js, git, and WebPack with experience in full stack development using tools such as node.js and express.js.

Before transitioning to frontend development, I spent 4 years as a UX/UI designer. I have excelled in interface design, requirements gathering, and UX research, with a particular focus on complex projects in various subject areas

Portfolio: http://github.com/mtsoy123

Skills

HTML, CSS, SASS, React.js, Redux, Typescript, JavaScript, Vue.js, English, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Git, UX, UI

Experience

Freelance

Frontend developer | 10/2022 - Present

- Developed fully-adaptive landing pages for small customers using HTML, SCSS, and vanilla JavaScript, while following best practices in frontend development.
- Created maintainable SCSS-styles and worked with BEM to ensure the maintainability of the codebase.
- Communicated effectively with customers, quickly immersed into new subject areas, and completed tasks quickly and successfully.

NAUMEN | Saint Petersburg

UX/UI Designer | 03/2021 - 12/2021

- Designed the interface for a large service desk product, in close collaboration with analysts
- Created a highly informative dashboard and a map-based application for project management
- Maintained an organized internal knowledge base for all design materials

CRP lab | Saint Petersburg

UX/UI Designer | 05/2020 - 12/2020

- Designed interfaces for a variety of projects, including a crypto-exchanger, SPDM systems, and CRM systems for universities and European banks
- Gathered requirements, created wireframes and prototypes, designed visual elements, and tested designs to ensure they
 were user-friendly and intuitive
- · Communicated effectively with colleagues in different time zones in both Russian and English

EPAM | Saint Petersburg

Experience designer | 01/2018 - 01/2020

- Conducted UX research, including interviews with users, personality analysis, and competitor analysis
- Designed interfaces, created wireframes and prototypes, and tested designs to ensure they were user-friendly and intuitive
- Maintained an organized design system for all design materials

Education

Udemy

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Masterclass | 12/2022

- Gained knowledge and experience in analyzing code complexity, recursion, and common programming patterns.
- Acquired skills in implementing searching and sorting algorithms, manipulating data structures, and applying Dijkstra's Shortest Path Algorithm.
- Focused on building a problem-solving approach to develop solutions to complex problems.

Yandex.Practikum

Web development | 09/2022

- Learned modern web development technologies to become a junior frontend developer, including expertise in HTML, CSS, JS, React.js, and Git.
- Developed several projects ranging from static one-page websites to SPAs with both frontend and backend components.
- Gained basic knowledge of Node.js and experience setting up servers using express.js and working with git and the WebPack project builder.
- Successfully completed training by creating a portfolio website that is both adaptive and responsive, reviewed and passed by a mentor.

Saint Petersburg State University of Telecommunications | Saint Petersburg Information Technologies and Communication Systems | 07/2019 GPA: 4,3/5

Paper on Research of the ACM mode of the DVB-S2 standard and its implementation into the digital television network

Languages

English, Russian